publicmobile.ca 2014-11-30

# Privacy with Public Mobile

Privacy with Public Mobile
At Public Mobile, we respect our customers’ privacy and take great care to safeguard their personal information.¹
We have developed this Privacy Policy to inform you about our privacy practices, which reflect the requirements
of Canada’s privacy legislation, the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act, and our own
continuing commitment to customer privacy.
We want you to understand the purposes for which we collect personal information about our customers. And we
want to be sure that we have your consent to continue to collect, use and disclose your personal information for
those purposes. The following is a brief summary of our privacy practices.
Why do we collect personal information?
If you are a Public Mobile customer, Public Mobile has some basic information about you. We understand that some
of this information is private, which is why we collect personal information only for the following purposes:
• To establish and maintain a responsible commercial relationship with you and to provide ongoing service. For
   example, when you apply for services, we collect information that allows us to confirm your identity and credit
   history so that we can accurately bill and collect for the products and services that you receive from us. We may
   collect credit card or bank account information if you prefer the convenience of pre-authorized payment for
   services.
• To understand your needs and preferences. We maintain a record of the products and services you receive from us,
   and we may ask for additional information so that we can serve you better. For example, we will ask for your email
   address, if you wish to pay your bills electronically.
• To develop, enhance, market or provide products and services. For example, we look at how our customers use our
   products and services, so that we can understand how to improve them. From time to time, we may review and
   analyze your use of our products and services to help us provide better product recommendations and special
   offers that we think will interest you.
• To manage and develop our business and operations. For example, we analyze customer usage of our networks
   and facilities to help us manage them efficiently and plan for future growth. Telephone calls to or from Public Mobile
   service representatives may be monitored or recorded for quality assurance purposes.
• To meet legal and regulatory requirements. For example, we may collect information in response to a court order, or
   to satisfy a request by the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission, herein referred to as the
   CRTC, for information about a customer complaint and how it was resolved.
When do we disclose personal information?
There are a variety of circumstances where we may need to disclose some personal information about our customers.
Subject to applicable CRTC regulations, we may disclose personal information, on a confidential basis with the
information to be used only for the purpose for which it was disclosed, to:
• a person seeking information as an agent of a customer, such as a customer’s legal representative, or as an
   authorized user under his or her account, if we are satisfied that the person is authorized to receive the information;
• other Public Mobile business units to help us serve our customers better and to provide them with services from
   different parts of our company;
• another telecommunications company for the efficient and cost-effective provision of telecommunications services,
   such as the information required to facilitate the porting of services between carriers;
• a company involved in supplying a customer with telecommunications or directory related services, for example,
   Yellow or White Page listings;
• a company or individual hired by Public Mobile to perform functions on its behalf, such as research or data
   processing;
• a third party to evaluate a customer’s creditworthiness or to collect an account;
• a credit-reporting agency;
• a public authority or agent of a public authority if, in the reasonable judgment of Public Mobile, it appears that there
   is imminent danger to life or property which could be avoided or minimized by disclosure of the information. If a
   customer dials 911, for example, we will provide the customer’s name, telephone number, address and other location
   information to the emergency agency;
• our program partners or to third-party agents responsible for administering special Public Mobile offers or
   programs;
• third parties in connection with the sale of parts of our business, the sale or securitization of assets, or the merger or
   amalgamation of part or all of our business with other entities. Since customer and account information will normally
   be a part of such transactions, we may use or disclose such information to other parties included in the transaction,
   as part of due diligence and/or on completion of the transaction; or
• a government agency or other third party, if required to meet legal and regulatory requirements, such as responding
   to a court order.
How do we protect your personal information?
In order to protect your personal information and your right to privacy, Public Mobile will:
• protect your personal information with appropriate security safeguards;
• protect the confidentiality of your personal information when dealing with other companies;
• strive to keep your personal information as accurate and up-to-date as is necessary for the Identified Purposes
   (defined below); and
• respond to your requests for access to your personal information.
Public Mobile will not collect, use or disclose your personal information for any purpose other than those identified in
this Commitment, your Customer Service Agreement, or our Service Terms, except with your consent (the “Identified
Purposes”). For greater clarity, unless you provide express consent Public Mobile will not:
• share your personal information with or sell it to third-party marketers; or
• use your personal information to enable third-party targeted advertisements.
Moreover, Public Mobile does not collect information about the websites you viewed (except visits to our own Web
sites, which we use to optimize our Public Mobile Web properties), your internet search history or the content of the
applications you use.
Personal information collected by Public Mobile may be stored and processed in Canada or another country. In either
case, the information is protected with appropriate security safeguards, but may be available to government agencies
under applicable law.
What are your choices?
We would like to have your consent to continue to collect, use and disclose your personal information for the
Identified Purposes. However, we want you to know that you do have choices and can refuse or withdraw your
consent as follows:
• You may have your name removed from our telephone, mail or email marketing lists. We use these lists to inform
   you of relevant products, services and special offers that may be of benefit to you.
• Our directory publisher (Yellow Pages Group) makes available lists of published names, addresses and phone
   numbers to selected organizations for a fee. You may choose to be excluded from these lists (non-published names,
   addresses and phone numbers are automatically excluded).
• You may refuse to provide personal information to us. You may also withdraw your consent at any time, subject to
   legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. However, in either case, this may limit our ability to serve you.
For further information, please contact us at 1.855.220.2400 or privacy@publicmobile.ca. Unless you tell us otherwise,
we will assume that we have your consent to continue to collect, use and disclose your personal information for the
Identified Purposes.
¹In this Privacy Commitment, the words “we” or “Public Mobile” refer to TELUS Corporation and its subsidiary companies, as they may exist from
time to time, including those subsidiaries or divisions that carry on business under the names TELUS, TELUS Communications Company, TELUS
Mobility, TELUS Quebec, Koodo, Black’s, PC mobile and Public Mobile, but not including TELUS Health. The words “we” and “Public Mobile” do not
include independent dealers and distributors of Public Mobile products and services.
Effective April 4, 2014
